Finding Aid for the Lucile, Lady Duff-Gordon Drawings LSC.0624
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 142, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [sheer gray-colored jacket with floral designs and blue and black trimmings, over pink top and sky blue skirt]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 149; Foxing on top right-hand edge and bottom right-hand corner, smudging along right edge, bottom left-hand corner, and upper left-hand area, white-out with grime on middle top area (around sketch of hat). (Box 15)
- 143, pen sketch of back view and skirt by itself on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature and L. Duff Gordon signature, [tan colored two piece dress suit with black buttons, and brown colored folded collar and cuffs]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 150; Foxing on bottom left and right-hand corners,and middle right-hand area, smudging along all four edges, peeled spots on middle top area. (Box 15)
- 144, LDG signature, "Sadko," [long bright red dress with gray fur-like bands on top portion, red ribbons along front and high, folded collar]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 151; Foxing on upper and middle left-hand edge and bottom right-hand edge, smudging on lower and upper right-hand areas, and lower left-hand area, scratched top edge, "30" written and erased on top right-hand corner. (Box 16)
- 145, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, Lucile signature and LDG signature, [off-the-shoulder blue and purple dress with silver designs, thin red sash across bodice and fan-shaped design on bodice]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 152; Foxing on upper right and left-hand areas, middle left-hand area, bottom left-hand area and right-hand corner, smudging on bottom right-hand corner, bent upper left and right-hand corners, peeled top edge with glue-like residues. (Box 16)
- 146, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, LDG signature, [off-the-shoulder pink dress with ruffles and designs, sheer pink sleeves and blue silver-printed sash trimmed yellow]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 153; Foxing on upper right-hand area, smudging on middle bottom area and middle right-hand area, bent left-hand corner, glue- like residues on top edge. (Box 16)
- 147, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature and LDG signature, [pale blue colored dress with ruffled design running vertically down the front, sheer sleeved jacket with flower prints and shoulders lined with fur, pink sash]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 154; Foxing along bottom, left, and right-hand areas, smudging along bottom and left-hand edges, and top middle and right-hand areas. (Box 16)
- 148, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, L. Duff Gordon signature, "A Fateful Moment," [off-the-shoulder dress with white lacy bodice and black silver-flower printed skirt, long wintergreen sash with silver prints and lined with fur]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 155; Foxing on upper left and right-hand corners and bottom left-hand corner, smudging on bottom left and right-hand corners, middle right-hand area and upper left-hand area, slightly striated top edge. (Box 16)
- 149, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, Lucile signature and LDG signature, [magenta colored two piece dress suit with buttons and tassels on front, gray fur collar and cuffs, with matching gray fur cap and magenta tassel]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 156; Foxing on middle right-hand area, and lower right and left-hand corners, smudging on top, bottom, right, and left-hand areas, white-out grime on middle area around sketch. (Box 16)
- 150, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, LDG signature, "Salambo," [dark blue jacket with silver, blue, and wintergreen designs on sleeves, purple inner lining with high fur banded collar and cuffs, blue tassel in front]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 157; Foxing on upper right-hand area and middle left-hand area, smudging on middle right-hand area, upper left-hand corner, and lower right-hand area, white-out grime on middle lower area, around sketch, glue-like residues on top edge. (Box 16)
- 151, "Miss Hampton," [blue sheer overcoat with gold flower prints and squared black fur designs, high collar, and pink flower corsage]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 158; Foxing along top edge, upper left-hand corner, and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on top right-hand area, middle left- hand area, and bottom left-hand corner, bent upper right-hand corner, scratched top edge with glue-like residues. (Box 16)
- 152, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, "Miss Hampton," sleeveless blue dress with transparent outer layer, V-shaped bodice, and colorful floral design on front]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 159; Foxing on upper right-hand edge, smudging on lower right-hand area, bent upper right-hand corner, slightly peeled top edge. (Box 16)
- 153, "Miss Hampton," [two-piece dress suit with black jacket top and gray-blue skirt with two black band designs, forest green trimmed collar and blue-gray belt]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 160; Foxing on top edge, bottom area, and middle right-hand area, smudging on upper middle area and bottom left-hand corner, bent upper left-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 16)
- 154, "Miss Hampton," [light purple dress with silver and lavender designs along front, sheer sleeved jacket with red floral prints and light-blue stripes, silver tassels along front of jacket and shoulders lined with fur]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 161; Foxing along bottom edge, middle left and right-hand areas, and upper left-hand edge, pencil mark on bottom left-hand corner, grease spots on upper left and right-hand corners, white-out grime on middle area, around sketch. (Box 17)
- 155, "Miss Hampton," [off-the-shoulder pale pink dress with white lacy designs, pale blue sash, small blue and purple flower designs on skirt and bodice]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 162; Foxing along top edge, middle and lower left-hand edges, and lower right-hand area, smudging on upper right-hand area and bottom right-hand corner, peeled spot on middle right-hand area, bent upper left and right-hand corners, glue-like residue along top. (Box 17)
- 156, "Miss Hampton," [sleeveless black dress with V-shaped bodice and black transparent outer layer, sequin-like design on dress]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 163; Foxing on middle right-hand area and bottom left and right-hand corners, smudging on middle left and right-hand edges, yellow colored spots on middle right-hand area, faint illegible writing on upper right-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 17)
- 157, "Miss Hampton," [pink and silver overcoat with pink flower prints, high double fur lined collar and cuffs with purple and red trimmings, pink tassel on front]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 164; Foxing on middle right-hand edge, upper right-hand corner, and middle lower area, smudging along bottom area, middle left-hand area, and middle top area, bent upper left and right-hand corners. (Box 17)
- 158, "Miss Hampton's Wedding," [pale blue dress with white trimmings and transparent sleeves, pale blue floral designs on dress underneath, ruffled collar and blue ribbon belt, matching pale blue ribboned hat]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 165; Foxing on upper right edge, middle left-hand area, and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on bottom left and right areas, and upper right-hand corner, "matron of honor" written in pencil on upper right corner, white out grime on various areas on sketch. (Box 17)
- 159, "Miss Hampton's Wedding," [pale blue dress with white trimmings and transparent sleeves, pale blue floral designs on inner white dress and blue ribbon sash, matching pale blue and white bonnet]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 166; Foxing on top left-hand corner, and bottom area, smudging on top and bottom left-hand corners, peeled spots on middle right-hand area, white-out grime on various areas on sketch, slightly striated top edge. (Box 17)
- 160, "Miss Hampton's Wedding," [pale blue and white colored dress with long sashes down middle, with floral designs on bottom with white fur trimmings, blue ribbon belt]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 167; Foxing along bottom and left sides, bent bottom left-hand corner. (Box 17)
- 161, "Miss Hampton's Wedding," [white dress with pale blue floral designs with pale blue top and white fur trimmings, short sashes down the middle]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 168; Foxing along left and top sides, bent upper and bottom left corners, grime on bottom of sketch. (Box 17)
- 162, "Miss Hampton," [brown two piece dress with buttons, and fur collar and cuffs, with matching fur hat and orange tassel]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 169; Foxing along top, left and right sides, bent upper right and bottom left-corners. (Box 17)
- 163, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, "Miss Hampton," [off-the-shoulder layered red dress with stripes along hems and sheer flared sleeves, cross-crossed bodice]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 170; Foxing on all four sides, bent upper and lower left-hand corners. (Box 17)
- 164, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, "Miss Hampton," [green dress with floral designs and off-the-shoulder peasant blouse with multi-colored ribbons around bodice]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 171; Foxing on top and left sides, peeled area on bottom left-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 18)
- 165, "Miss Hampton's Wedding," [wedding dress with intricate floral designs and white trimmings with white gloves and lace veil]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 172; Foxing on upper right-hand corner and top area, long cut on left side, colored smudge on bottom left-hand corner, grime on sketch. (Box 18)
- 166, "Miss Hampton's Wedding," [long white dress with intricate floral designs and long veil and three-fourth sleeves]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 173; Foxing on top and bottom areas, smudges on upper left and right-hand corners, and bottom right-hand corner. (Box 18)
- 167, "Miss Hampton's Mother," [lavender dress with fur trimmings around waist and collar, sheer top with lavender stripes and tasseled sash]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 174; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 18)
- 168, "Miss Hampton," [off-the-shoulder black dress with white leaf designs around bosom, and black feathered fan]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 175; Foxing on bottom left-hand corner and middle left-hand side, peeled top edge, grime on middle left area around sketch, bent upper left and right-hand corners. (Box 18)
- 169, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [flowing green robe with tasseled cuffs and pale blue dress underneath with silver ribbon sash]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 176; Foxing on bottom and upper right-hand areas, small hole on bottom left-hand area, peeling on middle bottom area and top, grime on middle left-hand area. (Box 18)
- 170, "Miss Hampton," [off-the-shoulder pink peasant dress with red and green trimmings on hem of skirt, and silver lace running down skirt, fan-shaped lace on bodice]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 177; Foxing on top area, smudging on middle left-hand area, bent upper left and right and lower left-hand corners. (Box 18)
- 171, pencil sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, "Miss Hampton," [sleeveless pleated blue-green dress with floral designs and green ribbon down the front]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 178; Striated top and bottom edges, bent upper right-hand edge and upper left-hand corner and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on upper right-hand area, grime on lower right-hand side of sketch. (Box 18)
- [no number], pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, "Miss Hampton," [sheer pink dress with silver designs and silver tassels, with polka-dotted patterns, turquoise sash underneath]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 179; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner and smudging on middle left-hand, top, and bottom areas, bent top edge. (Box 18)
- 172, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [blue-gray button down dress with red, blue, and green speckled collar, with beret]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 180; Foxing on upper right and left-hand areas, smudging on bottom right-hand area. (Box 18)
- 173, [orange-pink layered dress with ruffled oblong shaped hems and sheer yellow top trimmed with ruffles, and wide-brimmed hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 181; Foxing on bottom area, smudge on lower right-hand area, indentation on middle left-hand area by sketch. (Box 19)
- 174, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [pink frilly silver design printed dress trimmed with pink lace and blue waist]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 182; Foxing on bottom left and right-hand corners and middle right-hand area, bent left-hand corner and top right-hand edge. (Box 19)
- 175, colored sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, LDG signature, ""Vision Fugitive," good vs bad feel. 1916," [pale yellow dress with silver stripes, sheer top with pink and purple trimmings and speckled designs, yellow and green waistband]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 183; Foxing on upper middle and middle left-hand side, bent upper left and right-hand corners and bottom left-hand corners, smudging on bottom right-hand corner. (Box 19)
- 176, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [Asian-style dark purple dress with white flower prints and white sleeves with purple cuffs, tassel down the middle, yellow- tasseled sheer rice hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 184; Creased left-hand and bottom sides, smudging on bottom left-hand area, bent upper and right-hand corners. (Box 19)
- 177, [short green dress with purple trims and purple sash, green hat and purple stockings]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 185; Hole on upper right-hand area. (Box 19)
- 178, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [pink and yellow ruffled dress with contrasting pink sash and flowers on bodice]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 186; Foxing on lower right-hand and upper left-hand areas, smudging on bottom left-hand areas, bent top right edge. (Box 19)
- 179, [short blue dress with green buttons down front, green ribbon at waist and green stockings, with matching green and blue hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 187; Foxing on bottom and top right-hand corners, peeled top, colored spot on middle left-hand area, smudging on middle top area. (Box 19)
- 180, [black-and-white checkered short dress with pink trimmings and apron-designed front, matching bandanna hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 188; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner, smudging on top and bottom left-hand corners. (Box 19)
- 181, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature and two Lucy Duff Gordon stamps, [blue and white striped ruffled dress with pink flower prints and sheer sleeves, and yellow equestrian-styled hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 189; Foxing on bottom, smudging on middle right-hand side and upper and lower left-hand sides, bent upper left corners and top right edge. (Box 19)
- 182, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [long white dress with silver and green sequined bodice, and pink scarf with silver prints]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 190; Colored spot on middle top area, smudging on upper and bottom right-hand areas, bent upper right and left-hand corners. (Box 19)
- 183, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [grey dress with white ruffles and black sash with black jacket with lace cuffs and wide-brimmed black hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 191; Foxing on bottom left-hand area and middle right-hand area, smudging on bottom right-hand corner and top and middle left hand areas, bent upper right-hand corner, glue like residue on top edge. (Box 20)
- 184, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [high-waisted white v-neck dress with floral designs]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 192; Foxing on top and bottom right corners and middle left area, smudging on top middle right area and upper and bottom left- hand corners and bottom right-hand corner, prick on lower right-hand area, bent upper left and right-hand corners, peeled top edge. (Box 20)
- 185, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [long purple cape with gold military-styled buttons in front and grey blue dress underneath]., 1916-1917; UCLA Drawing No. 193; Foxing on top edge and bottom right-hand area, smudging on left middle area and along bottom edge, striated bottom edge. (Box 20)
- 186, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [pale purple and blue layered dress with floral designs and green floral printed sash and matching parasol]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 194; Foxing on upper left-hand area and middle bottom area, smudging on bottom left-hand area, bent upper left and right-hand corners, grime on upper middle area of sketch, glue like residue on top edge. (Box 20)
- 195, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [green and silver flowered printed robe with silver tassels on sleeves over emerald green floral printed dress]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 195; Foxing along right and bottom edges and lower and middle left-hand edges, crease along top area, slightly bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 20)
- 188, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [high collared grey long trench coat with gold buckled belt, collar and cuffs and bright red cap]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 196; Foxing on top left and right-hand corners, bottom right-hand area and bottom left-hand corner, smudging on bottom left and right-hand corners and middle left-hand edge, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 20)
- 189, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [sheer silver striped top with flowy blue silver printed skirt and orange, blue sash with silver fringe]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 197; Foxing on top edge middle left area and bottom left-hand corner, smudging on upper right-hand area, middle area, and bottom edge, indent on top right edge. (Box 20)
- 190, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [asian-styled pale blue robe with silver designs and red and turquoise hems on top of blue silver dress with green and blue waist band and purple, green, and orange tassels]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 198; Foxing on lower left-hand corner, bent upper right and left-hand corners, smudging on middle left-hand area, indented top right edge. (Box 20)
- 191, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [pale blue long-sleeved dress with blue ruffles, white-ruffled collar, and sheer blue sleeves]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 199; Foxing on lower bottom area, lower right-hand area, and middle left-hand area, smudging on upper left-hand corner and middle and lower right-hand area, net upper right-hand corner, grease-like spot on middle left-hand area. (Box 20)
- 192, colored sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [V-necked gray dress with white ruffles running vertically along dress, sheer white sleeves with gray ruffled-bands, black waistband and wide-brimmed black hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 200; Foxing on middle bottom and right-hand area, smudging on upper left-hand corner, middle right-hand area, and bottom left- hand corner, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 20)
- 193, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [dress with pink bodice and long gray wrapped skirt portion, white jacket with green cuffs]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 201; Foxing on upper left-hand edge, smudging on all four corners and upper middle area, white-out grime on middle area, around sketch, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 21)
- 194, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [two piece dress suit with white blue-buttoned blouse and long blue skirt with black belt, matching blue and white hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 202; Foxing on top left-hand edge, top right-hand corner, and bottom area, smudging along bottom, left, and right-hand edges, discoloration band on bottom area, white-out grime on middle area, on sketch, red spot on middle right-hand area. (Box 21)
- 195, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [off-the-shoulder long purple dress with dark purple ruffles, long sleeves with ruffled cuffs, colorful sprinkle design along top of bodice, and gold design prints on middle of bodice]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 203; Foxing along on upper area, smudging on upper right-hand area and lower left and right-hand corners, white out grime in middle area, on sketch, discoloration band along top, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 21)
- 196, colored sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [gold flower printed long white dress with blue sash, tapered skirt portion]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 204; Foxing on bottom left-hand corner, smudging on top and bottom left-hand corner, slightly bent left-hand corner, peeled top edge. (Box 21)
- 197, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [off-the-shoulder green and white striped dress, with colorful sprinkle designed ruffle top, green, white, blue and red sash]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 205; Foxing along top edge, upper left and right-hand edges, and bottom edge, smudging on all four corners, bent upper left and right-hand corners, indent on top right-hand edge, peeled top edge. (Box 21)
- 198, pencil sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, Lucy Duff Gordon stamp signature, [white long-sleeved dress with pink buttons and belt, pink designs on ruffled collar, cuffs, and upper skirt portion]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 206; Foxing on upper right-hand area and top middle area, smudging on middle area, on sketch and around it, indent on top right-hand edge. (Box 21)
- 199, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, LDG signature with date, [white sleeveless dress with silver designs and white bows, layered skirt portion]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 207; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner, smudging on upper left and right-hand corners, upper middle area, and bottom area, bent upper right-hand corner, white-out grime on middle area, on sketch. (Box 21)
- 200, pencil sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [long black robe with purple and pale green collar and cuffs, intricately designed tassels on front]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 208; Smudging on bottom left-hand corner, fingerprint marks on middle left-hand area, grease spot on middle right-hand area, white-out grime in lower middle area, on and around sketch, bent upper right-hand corner, glue-like residue along top edge. (Box 21)
- 201, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [off-the-shoulder emerald green dress with silver and green flower designs on skirt, puffy outer green skirt layer]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 209; Foxing on upper left-hand corner and bottom right-hand corner, erased pencil Writing on upper right-hand corner, white-out grime on middle area, on and around sketch, striated bottom edge, peeled spot on upper left area, bent top left and right corners. (Box 21)
- 202, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [boat-neck light yellow dress with white lacing and pink leaf designs, and pink sash]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 210; Foxing on bottom area, smudging on top and bottom left-hand corners, and middle area, bent upper left-hand corner, peeled spots on upper area, black spot on upper right-hand corner. (Box 21)
- 203, [long black and white overcoat with high collar, and wide tasseled cuffs, white floral printed inner lining, and green dress underneath]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 211; Smudging on top right-hand corner, middle left-hand area, and bottom right-hand area, white-out grime on middle right-hand and lower area, on sketch, peeled top edge, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 22)